Guide to the Carlton E. Morse Papers, 1932-1982
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1. Bound Scripts, 164 Volumes
  - THE AMERICAN SCENE 1947
    - 7. THE CASE OF ROBERT
    - 8. PAEN TO DAVID
    - 9. TEMPTATION OF PROF. & MRS. HEATH
    - 10. I, JANE, G. I. 39034794
    - 11. MEMORIAL
    - 12. THE CATERPILLAR OR THE PARACHUTE
    - 13. PROPOSED OUTLINE FOR THE CHARLOTTE GREENWOOD SHOW
    - 14. NORTH CAROLINA
    - 15. THE COFFIN
    - 16. THE DEAD
  - Bound Volumes of HIS HONOR JUDGE FITZ Radio Scripts
    - 13 Episodes (Volume Vols. 125-126)
    - from Oct. 23, 1945 to Jan. 8, 1946 (Volume 1)
    - Jan. 15, 1946 to April 9, 1946 (Volume 2)
  - Bound Volume of I LOVE ADVENTURE Radio Scripts
    - From April 25, 1948 to July 8, 1948 (Box 1, Volume Vol. 134)
  - THE UPPER ROOM Radio scripts
    - 1948 - 1949 (Volume Vol. 145)
  - MIXED DOUBLES TV Scripts
    - From Aug. 5 to Sept. 16, 1949 (Volume 1, Volume Vol. 146)
    - from Sept. 23 to Oct. 29, 1949 (Volume 2, Volume Vol.147)
  - Bound Volumes of FAMILY SKELETON Radio Shows
    - From June 8, 1953 to Aug. 7, 1953 (Volume Vols. 157-163, Volume 1)
    - Aug. 10, 1953 Sept. 8, 1953 (Volume 2)
    - Sept. 9, 1953 Oct. 14, 1953 (Volume 3)
    - Oct. 15, 1953 Nov. 17, 1953 (Volume 4)
    - Nov. 18, 1953 Jan. 1, 1954 (Volume 5)
    - Jan. 4, 1954 Feb. 4, 1954 (Volume 6)
    - Feb. 5, 1954 March 5, 1954 (Volume 7)
- Series 2. Newsclippings and Letters, 19 volumes
  - Scrapbooks (Box Box 1)
    - 1. Letters, 1940-1941
    - 2. Letters, 1941-1943
    - 3. Letters, 1944-1945
    - 4. Letters, 1946-1947
    - 5. Letters, 1946-1949
    - 1. Letters, 1936-1940 (Box Box 2)
    - 2. Letters, 1943-1944
    - 3. Letters, 1945-1946
    - 4. Letters, 1949-1950
    - 5.- 7. Scrapbooks of clippings
    - 1. - 7. Scrapbooks of clippings, including One Man's Family 20th anniversary blue volume (Box Box 3)
- Series 3. One Man's Family: 15 min. television films, 131 reels
  - Chap 1, March 1, 1954, Episode [1] (Box 6)
  - Chap 2, March 2, 1954, Episode [2] (Box 6)
  - March 3, 1954, Episode 3 (Box 6)
  - Chap 4, n. d., Episode [4] (Box 6)
  - March 5, 1954, Episode 5 (Box 6)
  - Chap 6, n. d., Episode [6] (Box 6)
  - Chap 7, March 9, 1954, Episode [7] (Box 6)
  - Chap 8, March 10, 1954, Episode [8] (Box 6)
  - Chap 9, n. d., Episode [9] (Box 6)
  - March 12, 1954, Episode 10 (Box 6)
  - March 15, 1954, Episode 11 (Box 6)
  - March 16, 1954, Episode 12 (Box 6)
  - March 17, 1954, Episode 13 (Box 6)
  - March 18, 1954, Episode 14 (Box 6)
  - March [19?] 1954, Episode 15 (Box 6)
  - March 22, 1954, Episode 16 (Box 6)
  - March 23, 1954, Episode 17 (Box 6)
  - March 24, 1954, Episode [18] (Box 6)
  - April 2, 1954, Episode 25 (Box 6)
  - April 5, [1954], Episode 26 (Box 8)
  - April 6, 1954, Episode 27 (Box 5)
  - April 9, 1954, Episode 30 (Box 8)
  - April 12, 1954, Episode 31 (Box 8)
  - April 15, 1954, Episode 34 (Box 8)
  - April 16, 1954, Episode 35 (Box 5)
  - April 20, 1954, Episode 37 (Box 5)
  - April 21, [1954], Episode 38 (Box 5)
  - April 22, [1954] 3919, Episode [39] (Box 5)
  - 3928, April 23, 1954, Episode [40] (Box 5)
  - April 26, 1954, Episode 41 (Box 5)
  - April 28, 1954, Episode 43 (Box 8)
  - April 15, 1954, Episode 44 (Box 8)
  - April 30, 1954, Episode 45 (Box 8)
  - May 3, 1954, Episode 46 (Box 5)
  - May 5, 1954, Episode 48 (Box 5)
  - May 6, 1954, Episode 49 (Box 5)
  - May 12, 1954, Episode 53 (Box 4)
  - April 29, [1954], Episode 54 (Box 8)
  - April 30, [1954], Episode 55 (Box 8)
  - May 18, 1954, Episode 57 (Box 4)
  - May 20, [1954], Episode 59 (Box 4)
  - May 21, 1954, Episode 60 (Box 5)
  - May 24, 1954, Episode 61 (Box 5)
  - May 25, 1954, Episode 62 (Box 5)
  - May 26, 1954, Episode 63 (Box 4)
  - May 27, 1954, Episode 64 (Box 5)
  - May 28, 1954, Episode 65 (Box 5)
  - May 13, 1954, Episode [66?] (Box 5)
  - June 3, 1954, Episode 69 (Box 4)
  - June 4, 1954, Episode 70 (Box 4)
  - June 7, 1954, Episode 71 (Box 4)
  - June 8, 1954, Episode 72 (Box 4)
  - June 9, 1954, Episode 73 (Box 4)
  - June 10, 1954, Episode 74 (Box 4)
  - June 11, 1954, Episode 75 (Box 4)
  - June 14, 1954, Episode 76 (Box 4)
  - June 15, 1954, Episode 77 (Box 4)
  - June 18, 1954, Episode 80 (Box 4)
  - June 25, 1954, Episode 85 (Box 4)
  - June 28, 1954, Episode 86 (Box 4)
  - June 29, 1954, Episode 87 (Box 4)
  - June 30, 1954, Episode 88 (Box 4)
  - July 1, 1954, Episode 89 (Box 9)
  - July 2, 1954, Episode 90 (Box 9)
  - July 7, 1954, Episode [91?] (Box 9)
  - July 8, 1954, Episode [92?] (Box 9)
  - July 9, 1954, Episode [93?] (Box 10)
  - July 12, 1954, Episode [94?] (Box 10)
  - July 13, 1954, Episode [95?] (Box 9)
  - July 19, 1954, Episode 96 (Box 10)
  - July 21, 1954, Episode 97 (Box 10)
  - July 22, 1954, Episode 98 (Box 10)
  - July 23, 1954, Episode 99 (Box 9)
  - July 26, 1954, Episode 100 (Box 9)
  - July 27, 1954, Episode 101 (Box 10)
  - July 28, 1954, Episode 102 (Box 9)
  - July 29, 1954, Episode 103 (Box 9)
  - July 30, 1954, Episode 104 (Box 9)
  - August 2, 1954, Episode 105 (Box 7)
  - August 3, 1954, Episode 106 (Box 8)
  - August 4, 1954, Episode 107 (Box 10)
  - August 5, 1954, Episode 108 (Box 8)
  - July 30, 1954[?], Episode 109 (Box 9)
  - August 9, 1954, Episode 110 (Box 8)
  - August 3, 1954 [?], Episode 111 (Box 10)
  - August 11, 1954, Episode 112 (Box 10)
  - August 12, 1954, Episode 113 (Box 10)
  - August 13, 1954, Episode 114 (Box 7)
  - August 16, 1954, Episode 115 (Box 10)
  - August 17, 1954, Episode 116 (Box 10)
  - August 18, 1954, Episode 117 (Box 10)
  - August 19, 1954, Episode [118?] (Box 8)
  - August 13, 1954 [?], Episode 119 (Box 10)
  - August 23, 1954, Episode 120 (Box 10)
  - August 25, 1954, Episode 122 (Box 10)
  - August 19, 1954 [?], Episode 123 (Box 8)
  - August 27, 1954, Episode [124?] (Box 10)
  - August 30, 1954, Episode 124 (Box 10)
  - August 30, 1954, Episode 125 (Box 10)
  - August 31, 1954, Episode [126?] (Box 10)
  - September 1, 1954, Episode 127 (Box 9)
  - September 2, 1954, Episode 128 (Box 8)
  - September 3, 1954, Episode 129 (Box 7)
  - [September]6, 1954, Episode 130 (Box 8)
  - September 7, 1954, Episode [131?] (Box 9)
  - September 8, 1954, Episode 132 (Box 9)
  - September 9, 1954, Episode 133 (Box 9)
  - September 13, 1954, Episode [135] (Box 9)
  - September 16, 1954, Episode 138 (Box 9)
  - September 17, 1954, Episode 139 (Box 9)
  - September 20, 1954, Episode 140 (Box 9)
  - September 15, 1954, Episode 142 (Box 9)
  - September 15, 1954, Episode 142[?] (Box 8)
  - September 23, 1954, Episode 143 (Box 9)
  - September 24, 1954, Episode [144?] (Box 9)
  - September 27, 1954, Episode 145 (Box 9)
  - September 28, 1954, Episode 146 (Box 9)
  - September 29, 1954, Episode 147 (Box 9)
  - September 23, 1954, Episode 148 (Box 9)
  - September 23, 1954, Episode 148 [?] (Box 9)
  - October 1, 1954, Episode [149] (Box 9)
  - October 4, 1954, Episode [150?] (Box 9)
  - 1 film undated and unnumbered (Box 7)
  - 1 film undated and unnumbered (Box 9)
  - 4 canisters of atmosphere shots (Box 9)
  - 3 canisters of background shots (Box 9)
- Series 4. Unpublished Manuscripts, Pamphlets and Other Materials, 21 items
  - UNPUBLISHED MANUSCRIPTS (Box Box 11)
    - 1. The Book of Monetti (Box Box 11)
    - 2. The Forever Odyssey (Box Box 11)
    - 3. Great Jupiter Zeus! or In The Beginning or How The World Began or Mt. Olympus Revisited (Box Box 11)
    - 4. Killer At The Wheel Book 1 Chapters 1 through 26, Book 2 Chapters 27 through 48 and Epilogue (Box Box 11)
    - 5. A Lavish of Sin (Box Box 11)
    - 6. One Man's Family (Beginning of novelization) (Box Box 11)
    - 7. The Other World of Carlton E. Morse (Box Box 11)
    - 8. Some Furtive Reflections (Box Box 11)
    - 9. The Widow With The Amputation (Box Box 11)
  - PAMPHLETS (Box Box 11)
    - 10. Barbour Family Album (Box Box 11)
    - 11. Barbour Family Scrapbook by William Pinky Barbour Herbert (Box Box 11)
    - 12. Chatter With The Batter, 1948 (Box Box 11)
    - 13. I Believe in America (Box Box 11)
    - 14. Jack's Camera Scrapbook (Box Box 11)
    - 15. Memory Book - Fanny Barbour (Box Box 11)
    - 16. One Man's Family Looks at Life (Box Box 11)
    - 17. A Short History of a Long Story, 1952.(bound in blue slipcase). (Box Box 11)
    - 18. Teddy Barbour's Diary, 1937. (Box Box 11)
    - 19. This I Give, (2 copies) (Box Box 11)
  - Other
    - 20. Photographs of cast of One Man's Family - should after scripts. (Box Box 11)
    - 21. Recording of One Man's Family - transferred To Archives of Recorded Sound (Box Box 11)
- Series 5. Oversized Scrapbooks, 4 volumes
  - 1934-36 (Oversize 1)
  - 1937-43 (Oversize 2)
  - 1943-50 (Oversize 3)
  - 1950-55 (Oversize 4)
- Series 6. ONE MAN'S FAMILY New York Shows: 1 hour television films, 87 reels
  - July 29, 1950, Episode 1
  - August 5, 1950, Episode 2
  - August 12, 1950, Episode 3
  - August 19, 1950, Episode 4
  - August 26, 1950, Episode 5
  - Sept. 2, 1950, Episode 6
  - Sept. 16, 1950, Episode 7
  - Sept. 23, 1950, Episode 8
  - Sept. 30, 1950, Episode 9
  - Oct. 7, 1950, Episode 10
  - Oct. 14, 1950, Episode 11
  - Oct. 21, 1950, Episode 12
  - Oct. 28 & Nov. 14, 1950, Episode 13 & 14
  - Nov. 11, 1950, Episode 15
  - Nov. 18, 1950, Episode 16
  - Nov. 25, 1950, Episode 17
  - Dec. 2, 1950, Episode 18
  - Dec. 9, 1950, Episode 19
  - Dec. 16, 1950, Episode 20
  - Dec. 23, 1950, Episode 21
  - Dec. 30, 1950, Episode 22
  - Jan. 13, 1951, Episode 23
  - Jan. 20, 1951, Episode 24
  - Jan. 27, 1951, Episode 25
  - Jan. 27, 1951, Episode 26
  - Feb. 3, 1951, Episode 27
  - missing (Feb. 10, 1951), Episode 28
  - Feb. 17, 1951, Episode 29
  - Feb. 24, 1951, Episode 30
  - Mar. 3, 1951, Episode 31
  - Mar. 10, 1951, Episode 32
  - Mar. 17, 1951, Episode 33
  - Mar. 24, 1951, Episode 34
  - Mar. 31, 1951, Episode 35
  - Apr. 7, 1951, Episode 36
  - Apr. 14, 1951, Episode 37
  - Apr. 21, 1951, Episode 38
  - Apr. 28, 1951, Episode 39
  - May 5, 1951, Episode 40
  - May 12, 1951, Episode 41
  - May 19, 1951, Episode 42
  - May 21, 1951, Episode 43
  - June 2, 1951, Episode 44
  - June 9, 1951, Episode 45
  - June 16, 1951, Episode 46
  - June 23, 1951, Episode 47
  - June 30, 1951, Episode 48
  - July 7, 1951, Episode 49
  - July 14, 1951, Episode 50
  - July 21, 1951, Episode 51
  - Sept. 29, 1951, Episode 52
  - Oct. 6, 1951, Episode 53
  - missing, Episode 54
  - Oct. 20, 1951, Episode 55
  - Oct. 27, 1951, Episode 56
  - Nov. 3,10,17, 1951, Episode 57, 58 & 59
  - Nov. 24, 1951, Episode 60
  - Dec. 1, 1951, Episode 61
  - Dec. 8, 1951, Episode 62
  - Dec. 15, 1951, Episode 63
  - Dec. 22, 1951, Episode 64
  - Dec. 29, 1951, Episode 65
  - Jan. 5, 1952, Episode 66
  - Jan. 12, 1952 (2), Episode 67
  - Jan. 19, 1952, Episode 68
  - Jan. 26, 1952, Episode 69
  - Feb. 2, 1952, Episode 70
  - Feb. 2 & 9, 1952, Episode 71
  - Feb. 16, 1952, Episode 72
  - Feb. 23, 1952, Episode 73
  - March 1, 1952, Episode 74
  - March 8, 1952, Episode 75
  - March 15, 1952, Episode 76
  - March 22, 1952, Episode 77
  - March 29, 1952, Episode 78
  - Apr. 5, 1952, Episode 79
  - Apr. 12, 1952, Episode 80
  - Apr. 19, 1952 (2), Episode 81
  - April 26, 1952, Episode 82
  - May 3, 1952, Episode 83
  - May 10, 1952, Episode 84
  - May 17, 1952, Episode 85
  - May 24, 1952, Episode 86
  - May 31, 1952, Episode 87
  - June 7, 1952, Episode 88
  - June 14, 1952, Episode 89
  - June 21, 1952, Episode 90